<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Aditya Rachman Putra</title><link>https://banditelol.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Aditya Rachman Putra</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><copyright>Copyright © 2023, Aditya Rachman Putra.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://banditelol.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>(TIL) Using Sympy to (not only) Generate Latex</title><link>https://banditelol.github.io/2023/03/19/til-using-sympy-to-not-only-generate-latex/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://banditelol.github.io/2023/03/19/til-using-sympy-to-not-only-generate-latex/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been writing Latex manually for a while, especially when working on a more scientifically-intensive notebook in python. While it&amp;rsquo;s not that hard to do, sometimes it requires patience and detail. And today I learned that I could use python&amp;rsquo;s sympy to alleviate some of the work. Usually I just do the following:
how I usually use Latex in my notebook
It&amp;rsquo;s fine and for simple equation it works just fine.</description></item><item><title>(ID) Rumah Ngidam-ngidaman</title><link>https://banditelol.github.io/essays/2023-03-18-rumah-ngidaman/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://banditelol.github.io/essays/2023-03-18-rumah-ngidaman/</guid><description>Rumah Ngidam-ng(idaman) Salah satu milestone yang mungkin sering terpikirkan oleh orang-orang seusia saya teh (terutama setelah nikah), pengen punya rumah sendiri atau pengen punya hunian sendiri (karena bisa jadi apartmen juga kalau jaman sekarang mah). Jadi waktu salah satu sahabat saya ada yang lagi riset tentang hal ini (preferensi hunian), saya langsung berfikir kalau ini bisa sekalian saya jadiin tempat dan prompt untuk membantu saya berfikir (+ bahan blog). Kurang lebih tujuan dari risetnya adalah:</description></item><item><title>Scraping the Surface of Airtable (Part 2)</title><link>https://banditelol.github.io/2020/09/10/scraping-the-surface-of-airtable-part-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://banditelol.github.io/2020/09/10/scraping-the-surface-of-airtable-part-2/</guid><description>Photo by jimmy teoh from Pexels
Before we start, let&amp;rsquo;s appreciate the fact that the first part is 2 yrs old! Anyway, after 2 years of working on another things, I came back around to the same problem today. Still the same idea as part one, that is how can i connect multiple bases without the need of logging into airtable. This part will be built on top of the first one, or to summarize: turns out I&amp;rsquo;m on the right track and requestId doesn&amp;rsquo;t really matter too much, maybe I made mistake in copying it in the last post?</description></item><item><title>Learn Clojure Day 0</title><link>https://banditelol.github.io/2020/06/24/learn-clojure-day-0/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://banditelol.github.io/2020/06/24/learn-clojure-day-0/</guid><description>Photo by jimmy teoh from Pexels
I&amp;rsquo;ve wanted to learn functional programming for a while, and finding out about Athens and their use of Clojure gave me the final push to finally open up my terminal and start fiddling around with the language. And here I wanted to write why I am intrigued by Athens, and a bit of what small amount of clojure that I&amp;rsquo;ve learnt.
Second Brain and Athens I&amp;rsquo;ve spent the last 2 month using Roam Research to aid me in thinking and organize my private writing and journaling, also for a kind of CRM.</description></item><item><title>Cooking and Programming</title><link>https://banditelol.github.io/essays/2020-02-13-cooking-x-programming/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://banditelol.github.io/essays/2020-02-13-cooking-x-programming/</guid><description/></item><item><title>3 Things I learned on DevC Bandung Meetup (Pytorch)</title><link>https://banditelol.github.io/essays/2020-01-29-devc-pytorch-lessons/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://banditelol.github.io/essays/2020-01-29-devc-pytorch-lessons/</guid><description>This note is about what I learnt from FB Bandung DevC Meetup last Wednesday (2020-01-22), to be specific it is about Amajid Sinar Guntara - Jedi&amp;rsquo;s talk on using Pytorch from research to deployment. His original slide can be found on Bandung DevC Facebook Group. AS this note is about what I learnt, I may not cover all of his talk and will focus more on what interests me and also serve as my cue on what I want to learn next.</description></item><item><title>Searching for Indonesia Population</title><link>https://banditelol.github.io/2018/09/09/searching-for-indonesia-population/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://banditelol.github.io/2018/09/09/searching-for-indonesia-population/</guid><description>When talking about finding information online, I have quite a confidence in me. But today I learned that confidence is not enough, there is something more important. That is for the information itself to be available online.
The story goes like this,
Innocent Learning Today I’ve decided to continue my long delayed learning on Wes Bos’s JS30. The content of the exercise today (Day 6) is to create a type ahead for data on population in United States Cities.</description></item><item><title>Scraping the Surface of Airtable (Part 1)</title><link>https://banditelol.github.io/2018/09/08/scraping-the-surface-of-airtable-part-1/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://banditelol.github.io/2018/09/08/scraping-the-surface-of-airtable-part-1/</guid><description>Recently the company I’m working in started using and tinkering with this google sheets like relational database service (to be honest I think this description may be misleading, it will do you better to just checkout the product here. After tinkering around with it I’m wondering if I can just scrape data from airtable without the use of API and just the feature of view sharing.
But, before I continue, Disclaimer :</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://banditelol.github.io/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://banditelol.github.io/about/</guid><description>Hi, my name is Aditya Rachman Putra and I&amp;rsquo;m currently a Data Scientist in Pitik. I have always been passionate about solving problem using programming and data, which led me to pursue a career in this field. Over the years, I have gained extensive experience and knowledge in Product Development and End to End Data Stack, and have had the opportunity to work with a diverse range of clients and projects.</description></item></channel></rss>