<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Tech Blog on Aditya Rachman Putra</title><link>https://banditelol.github.io/</link><description>Recent content in Tech Blog on Aditya Rachman Putra</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><copyright>Copyright © 2023, Aditya Rachman Putra.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://banditelol.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Scraping the Surface of Airtable (Part 2)</title><link>https://banditelol.github.io/2020/09/10/scraping-the-surface-of-airtable-part-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://banditelol.github.io/2020/09/10/scraping-the-surface-of-airtable-part-2/</guid><description>Photo by jimmy teoh from Pexels
Before we start, let&amp;rsquo;s appreciate the fact that the first part is 2 yrs old! Anyway, after 2 years of working on another things, I came back around to the same problem today. Still the same idea as part one, that is how can i connect multiple bases without the need of logging into airtable. This part will be built on top of the first one, or to summarize: turns out I&amp;rsquo;m on the right track and requestId doesn&amp;rsquo;t really matter too much, maybe I made mistake in copying it in the last post?</description></item><item><title>Learn Clojure Day 0</title><link>https://banditelol.github.io/2020/06/24/learn-clojure-day-0/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://banditelol.github.io/2020/06/24/learn-clojure-day-0/</guid><description>Photo by jimmy teoh from Pexels
I&amp;rsquo;ve wanted to learn functional programming for a while, and finding out about Athens and their use of Clojure gave me the final push to finally open up my terminal and start fiddling around with the language. And here I wanted to write why I am intrigued by Athens, and a bit of what small amount of clojure that I&amp;rsquo;ve learnt.
Second Brain and Athens I&amp;rsquo;ve spent the last 2 month using Roam Research to aid me in thinking and organize my private writing and journaling, also for a kind of CRM.</description></item><item><title>Searching for Indonesia Population</title><link>https://banditelol.github.io/2018/09/09/searching-for-indonesia-population/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://banditelol.github.io/2018/09/09/searching-for-indonesia-population/</guid><description>When talking about finding information online, I have quite a confidence in me. But today I learned that confidence is not enough, there is something more important. That is for the information itself to be available online.
The story goes like this,
Innocent Learning Today I’ve decided to continue my long delayed learning on Wes Bos’s JS30. The content of the exercise today (Day 6) is to create a type ahead for data on population in United States Cities.</description></item><item><title>Scraping the Surface of Airtable (Part 1)</title><link>https://banditelol.github.io/2018/09/08/scraping-the-surface-of-airtable-part-1/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://banditelol.github.io/2018/09/08/scraping-the-surface-of-airtable-part-1/</guid><description>Recently the company I’m working in started using and tinkering with this google sheets like relational database service (to be honest I think this description may be misleading, it will do you better to just checkout the product here. After tinkering around with it I’m wondering if I can just scrape data from airtable without the use of API and just the feature of view sharing.
But, before I continue, Disclaimer :</description></item></channel></rss>