<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Essays on Aditya Rachman Putra</title><link>https://banditelol.github.io/essays/</link><description>Recent content in Essays on Aditya Rachman Putra</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><copyright>Copyright © 2023, Aditya Rachman Putra.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://banditelol.github.io/essays/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>(ID) Rumah Ngidam-ngidaman</title><link>https://banditelol.github.io/essays/2023-03-18-rumah-ngidaman/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://banditelol.github.io/essays/2023-03-18-rumah-ngidaman/</guid><description>Rumah Ngidam-ng(idaman) Salah satu milestone yang mungkin sering terpikirkan oleh orang-orang seusia saya teh (terutama setelah nikah), pengen punya rumah sendiri atau pengen punya hunian sendiri (karena bisa jadi apartmen juga kalau jaman sekarang mah). Jadi waktu salah satu sahabat saya ada yang lagi riset tentang hal ini (preferensi hunian), saya langsung berfikir kalau ini bisa sekalian saya jadiin tempat dan prompt untuk membantu saya berfikir (+ bahan blog). Kurang lebih tujuan dari risetnya adalah:</description></item><item><title>Cooking and Programming</title><link>https://banditelol.github.io/essays/2020-02-13-cooking-x-programming/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://banditelol.github.io/essays/2020-02-13-cooking-x-programming/</guid><description>This post is was originally written in 2018 and posted in my old blog. I thought the content was quite relevant today, so I decided to put it here and edited several things to make it easier to read (believe me, the original version is less thought out than I remembered it to be ).
Today I read this article in the Atlantic titled “The Why of Cooking”. At start, this article made me question myself on what it means to be able to cook.</description></item><item><title>3 Things I learned on DevC Bandung Meetup (Pytorch)</title><link>https://banditelol.github.io/essays/2020-01-29-devc-pytorch-lessons/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://banditelol.github.io/essays/2020-01-29-devc-pytorch-lessons/</guid><description>This note is about what I learnt from FB Bandung DevC Meetup last Wednesday (2020-01-22), to be specific it is about Amajid Sinar Guntara - Jedi&amp;rsquo;s talk on using Pytorch from research to deployment. His original slide can be found on Bandung DevC Facebook Group. AS this note is about what I learnt, I may not cover all of his talk and will focus more on what interests me and also serve as my cue on what I want to learn next.</description></item></channel></rss>